Guide to the Edwin Montefiore Borchard Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings and Speeches, 1910-1947; Series V; 3' (7 boxes)
  - Articles
    - "Confiscations: Extraterritorial and Domestic", 1937 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "Considerations in the Cataloguing and Classification of Roman Civil Law Books", 1923 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "Constitutionality of Declaratory Judgments", 1931 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "Contested Contractual Privileges", post-1929 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "Contractual Claims in International Law", 1913 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "Convicting the Innocent", 1932 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "Corrupt Practices Come Home to Roost", undated (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "The Customs Union Advisory Opinion", 1931 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "Decadence of the American Doctrine of Voluntary Expatriation" (editorial), 1931 (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "Decisions of the Claims Commissions, United States and Mexico" (editorial), post-1923 (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "The Declaratory Judgment as an Exclusive or Alternative Remedy", post-1932 (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "The Declaratory Judgment in the United States", post-1930 (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "Declaratory Judgments and Insurance Litigation", post-1934 (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "Declaratory Judgments (Festellungsurteil) in the United States", 1923? (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "Declaratory Judgments in Administrative Law", 1933 (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "Declaratory Judgments in Federal Courts" (editorial), 1932 (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "Declaratory Judgments in International Law" (editorial), undated (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "Declaratory Judgments in International Relations", post-1934 (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "Declaratory Judgments in New Jersey" (with Phoebe Morrison), 1932 (Box 140, Folder 1332)
    - "Declaratory Rulings", post-1940 (Box 140, Folder 1333)
    - "Definitions of International Law", post-1929 (Box 140, Folder 1333)
    - "Denial of Justice in International Law", undated (Box 140, Folder 1333)
    - "Diplomatic Protection of Citizens Abroad", 1931, undated (Box 140, Folder 1333)
    - "Discretion to Refuse Jurisdiction of Actions for Declaratory Judgments, post-1941 (Box 140, Folder 1333)
    - "The Distinction Between Legal and Political Questions", undated (Box 140, Folder 1333)
    - "The Doctrine of Non-Recognition" (with Phoebe Morrison), post-1931 (Box 140, Folder 1333)
    - "The Economic Boycott", 1932 (Box 140, Folder 1334)
    - "Effect of Naturalization Abroad of American Citizens on Their Minor Children Born in the United States"(editorial), 1936 (Box 140, Folder 1334)
    - "Effrontery", 1927? (Box 140, Folder 1334)
    - "Enemy Private Property" (editorial), post-1924, 1923 (Box 140, Folder 1334)
    - "The 'Enforcement' of Peace by 'Sanctions'" (editorial), 1933 (Box 140, Folder 1334)
    - "'Equal Protection' in Taxation in the United States", 1930 (Box 140, Folder 1334)
    - "Evolution in Legal Education", undated (Box 140, Folder 1334)
    - "Exempt Food Ships", undated (Box 140, Folder 1334)
    - "Extraterritorial Confiscations", 1942 (Box 140, Folder 1334)
    - "The Factor Extradition Case", 1934? (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "The Failure to Prosecute in Death or Personal Injury Cases", undated (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "The Federal Declaratory Judgments Act", 1934 (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "The Federal Tort Claims Act", 1945 (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "The Federal Tort Claims Bill", 1929?, 1933 (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "Pasquale Fiore", 1931 (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "Foreign Policy", 1921 (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "The Fourth Conference of Teachers of International Law and Related Subjects (editorial), 1930 (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "France Triumphant" (editorial), 1931 (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "French Administrative Law", 1933 (Box 141, Folder 1335)
    - "German Rearmament and United States Treaty Rights", 1935 (Box 141, Folder 1336)
    - "The German Ship Claims" (editorial), 1931 (Box 141, Folder 1336)
    - Intervention--The Truman Doctrine and the Marshall Plan, undated (Box 141, Folder 1336)
    - "The Hague Codification Conference", 1930 (Box 141, Folder 1336)
    - "Honor Among Allies", 1923 (Box 141, Folder 1336)
    - "How Far Must We Protect Our Citizens Abroad?", 1927 (Box 141, Folder 1336)
    - "How Shall We Settle Our Disputes with Latin America?", undated (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "Illusions about International Law", 1938 (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "Important Decisions of the Mixed Claims Commission, United States and Mexico"(editorial), post-1926 (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "Instances of Failure to Conform to State practice", undated (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - Institut für ausländisches öffentliches Recht und Völerrecht (editorial), 1930 (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "Institute of International Legal Research", undated (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "International Arbitration", 1930 (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "International Arbitration and the World Court", undated (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "The International Crisis", 1933 (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "International Irresponsibility", 1934 (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "International Law", 1932, post-1947 (Box 141, Folder 1337)
    - "International Law of War Since the War", 1934 (Box 141, Folder 1338)
    - "International Law Today", 1937 (Box 141, Folder 1338)
    - "International Loans and International Law", 1932 (Box 141, Folder 1338)
    - "International Relations of the American Continents", undated (Box 141, Folder 1338)
    - "The 'International Responsibility of States' at the Hague Codification Conference", 1931 (Box 141, Folder 1338)
    - Munroe Smith--An Appreciation, 1945? (Box 141, Folder 1338)
    - "Investors, Beware!", 1926 (Box 141, Folder 1338)
    - "Is Coercive Protection of Citizens Abroad Essential?", undated (Box 141, Folder 1338)
    - "Joint Action and Precedents", post-1917 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "Judicial Relief for Insecurity", 1933 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "Jurisprudence in Germany", 1912 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "Justiciability", 1936 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "The King May Do Wrong", 1926 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "The Kellogg Treaties Sanction War", 1928 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "The Kosenkina Case", 1948 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "La Follette and the Courts", 1924 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "The Law Division of the Library of Congress", 1929 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "The League of Nations", undated (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "The Lessons of the War", 1921 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "Limitations on Coercive Protection" (editorial), undated (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "Limitations on the Functions of International Courts", 1921 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "The Limits of American Foreign Policy", 1937 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "The Local Remedy Rule", 1934 (Box 141, Folder 1339)
    - "The Mavrommatis Concessions Case" (editorial), post-1925 (Box 141, Folder 1340)
    - "The Meaning of the Term: Neutrality", 1928 (Box 141, Folder 1340)
    - "The Mexican Complications", post-1917 (Box 141, Folder 1340)
    - "The 'Minimum Standard' of the Treatment of Aliens", 1938? (Box 141, Folder 1340)
    - "Misguided Diplomacy", (editorial) (Box 141, Folder 1340)
    - "The Monroe Doctrine", undated (Box 141, Folder 1340)
    - "John Bassett Moore", 1947 (Box 141, Folder 1340)
    - "Municipal Responsibility for the Torts of Policemen", 1932 (Box 141, Folder 1340)
    - "The Multilateral Treaty for the Renunciation of War" (editorial), undated (Box 141, Folder 1340)
    - "National Honor: Hughes vs. Hamilton"(editorial), 1923 (Box 141, Folder 1341)
    - "Nationality of Corporations", undated (Box 141, Folder 1341)
    - "Nationalization of Enemy Patents", undated (Box 141, Folder 1341)
    - "The Navicert System", 1939 (Box 141, Folder 1341)
    - "Neutral Embargoes and Commercial Treaties" (editorial), 1936 (Box 141, Folder 1341)
    - "Neutrality", 1935, post-1936 (Box 141, Folder 1341)
    - "Neutrality and Civil Wars" (editorial), post-1937 (Box 141, Folder 1342)
    - "Neutrality and Sanctions", post-1937 (Box 141, Folder 1342)
    - "Neutrality and Unneutrality" (editorial), 1938 (Box 141, Folder 1342)
    - "The Neutrality Claims Against Great Britain" (editorial), post-1927 (Box 141, Folder 1342)
    - "The Neutrality Legislation", pre-1936 (Box 141, Folder 1342)
    - "Note on Non-Belligerency in International Law", 1943 (Box 141, Folder 1342)
    - "Notes on Neutrality and the Administration's Policy", 1935 (Box 141, Folder 1342)
    - "Notes on Recognition", 1939 (Box 141, Folder 1342)
    - "On the International Responsibility of States for Damage Done in Their Territory to the Person or Property of Foreigners", 1937 (Box 142, Folder 1343)
    - "Opinions of the Mixed Claims Commission, United States and Germany (editorial, Part II), undated (Box 142, Folder 1343)
    - "Our Quarrel with Our Allies" (editorial), 1923 (Box 142, Folder 1343)
    - "Our Shipping Industry", undated (Box 142, Folder 1343)
    - "Our War Claims Against Britain" (editorial), 1926 (Box 142, Folder 1343)
    - "The Paris Settlement", 1925 (Box 142, Folder 1343)
    - "Judge Edwin B. Parker", 1930 (Box 142, Folder 1343)
    - "Peace Through an International Court", undated (Box 142, Folder 1343)
    - "Pecuniary Claims: Draft of Report on the Procedural Aspects of the Subject", 1937 (Box 142, Folder 1344)
    - "Pecuniary Claims: Draft Rules of Procedure", 1937 (Box 142, Folder 1344)
    - "William L. Penfield", 1932 (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "Permanent Court", undated (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "Permanent Court of International Justice", post-1937 (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "The Permanent Court of International Justice", 1923, post-1926 (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "The Policy of Committment or the Art of Tying One's Own Hands", 1949 (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "Political Theory and International Law", undated (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "The Power to Punish Neutral Volunteers in Enemy Armies" (editorial), 1938 (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "Private Pecuniary Claims Arising Out of War", 1915 (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "The Problem for the Reformer", undated (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "A Proposed Plan for Peace", undated (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "The Prospects for Neutrality", 1937 (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "The Protection of Citizens Abroad and Change of Original Nationality", 1933 (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "The Protection of Citizens Abroad by Armed Force", 1929 (Box 142, Folder 1345)
    - "Realism vs. Evangelism", 1934 (Box 142, Folder 1346)
    - "Rearmament of Germany", 1935 (Box 142, Folder 1346)
    - "Recent Developments in Declaratory Relief ", 1936-1937 (Box 142, Folder 1346)
    - "Recent Opinions of the Mixed Claims Commission, United States and Mexico" (editorial), 1931 (Box 142, Folder 1346)
    - "Recent Statutory Developments in Municipal Liability in Tort", 1936? (Box 142, Folder 1346)
    - "The Relation Between 'State' and 'Law'", 1927 (Box 142, Folder 1346)
    - "Reorganization of the World Court", 1930 (Box 142, Folder 1346)
    - "Report to the Secretary of State of Edwin Borchard, Member of the Inter-American Commission of Experts for the Codification of International Law, Concerning the Activities of the Commission in Connection with the Eighth Conference of American States at Lima, Peru, November-December, 1938", post-1938 (Box 142, Folder 1346)
    - "Reprisals on Private Property", 1935 (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "The Requisitioned German Ships in the United States", post-1917 (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "Research in International Law", 1930 (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "The Responsibility of a State", undated (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "The Responsibility of States", 1930 (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "Responsibility of States for Damage Done in Their Territories to the Person or Property of Foreigners" (editorial), undated (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "The Re-Statement of Sea Law", post-1928 (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "Restatement of the Law of Neutrality in Maritime War" (editorial), 1928? (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "The Resurrection of International Law", undated (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "Rough Draft Convention on Legal Assistance", 1937 (Box 142, Folder 1347)
    - "The Saint Lawrence Waterway and Power Project", post-1946 (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "Sanction, International", post-1932 (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "Sanctions v. Neutrality", 1935, post-1935 (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "Sanctions v. Neutrality: The Psychology of 'Enforcing Peace'", undated (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "The Sequestered Alien Property", 1922 (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "The Settlement of Our Neutrality Claims Against Great Britain", 1927 (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "The Settlement of War Claims Act of 1928" (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "Should the United States Assume Protective Responsibility for American Lives and Property in Foreign War Zones?", undated (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - State and Municipal Liability in Tort--Proposed Statutory Reform, post-1925 (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "Some Aspects of Comparative Law in the United States", 1932 (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "The Spanish Civil War and its Implications", post-1935 (Box 142, Folder 1348)
    - "State and Municipal Liability in Tort—Proposed Statutory Reform", 1934 (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "State Indemnity for Errors of Criminal Justice", 1913, 1941 (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "State Liability in Tort in Minnesota", 1948 (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "Statement on Supreme Court Measure", 1937 (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "Statement" (re: boycott against Japan), undated (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "Strength and Weakness of the New International Court", undated (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "Supplementary Report on Protection of Citizens Abroad", 1932 (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "Supreme Court", (and Police Power) (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "The Supreme Court and Private Rights", post-1937 (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "The Supreme Court and the Declaratory Judgment", 1928? (Box 143, Folder 1349)
    - "The Tacna-Arica Controversy", pre-1922 (Box 143, Folder 1350)
    - "Taney's Influence on Constitutional Law", undated (Box 143, Folder 1350)
    - "Ten Years After", 1927? (Box 143, Folder 1350)
    - "Theoretical Aspects of the International Responsibility of States", pre-1929 (Box 143, Folder 1350)
    - "Theories of Governmental Responsibility in Tort", 1928 (Box 143, Folder 1350)
    - "The Theory and Sources of International Law", 1931? (Box 143, Folder 1350)
    - "Those Advisory Opinions", 1926 (Box 143, Folder 1351)
    - "Three Hague Conventions on Nationality", 1937 (Box 143, Folder 1351)
    - "Tort Claims Against the Government", post-1948 (Box 143, Folder 1351)
    - "The Trading with the Enemy Act", 1925? (Box 143, Folder 1351)
    - "Transfer of Flag and the Declaration of London", 1923 (Box 143, Folder 1351)
    - "Treaties and Executive Agreements--A, Reply" (Box 143, Folder 1351)
    - "The Treatment of Enemy Private Property", 1948? (Box 143, Folder 1351)
    - "Treatment of Enemy Private Property in the United States Before the World War", 1928 (Box 143, Folder 1351)
    - "Unification of Rules of Law Relating to Extradition", 1931? (Box 143, Folder 1352)
    - "The Uniform Act on Declaratory Judgments", 1921 (Box 143, Folder 1352)
    - "The Uniform Declaratory Judgments Act", post-1933 (Box 143, Folder 1352)
    - "The U(nited) N(ations) and Mr. Hull's Reminiscences", 1949 (Box 143, Folder 1352)
    - "The United States and the Dawes Plan" (editorial), 1924 (Box 143, Folder 1352)
    - "The United States As a Factor in the Development of International Relations", undated (Box 143, Folder 1352)
    - "United States Foreign Policy" (editorial), 1949 (Box 143, Folder 1352)
    - "The United States-Panama Claims Arbitration"(editorial), post-1933 (Box 143, Folder 1352)
    - "The Unrecognized Government in American Courts", 1932 (Box 143, Folder 1352)
    - (Violations of International Law During World War I by France and Great Britain), undated (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "'War' and Peace'" (editorial), 1933 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "War, Neutrality and Non-Belligerency" (editorial), 1941 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "Was Norway Delinquent in the Case of Altmark?" (editorial), 1940 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "We Can Remain Neutral", 1935 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "What Are the Obstacles to Disarmament"(summary of a paper), undated (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "What Has Become of International Law?", 1947 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "What Is a 'Merchant Vessel'?", 1929 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "Winslow Resolution, J. J. 364" (suggested amendments), 1923 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "The World Court", 1930 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "The World Court Again", undated (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "World Use of German Property to Pay American Claims Be Confiscation?", 1926 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "The Wrong Road to Peace: Dangers in the Davis Commitment at Geneva", 1933 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
    - "Yntema, the Treaties with Germany and Compensation for War Damage", 1923 (Box 143, Folder 1353)
  - Memoranda
    - re: American interference in international politics for R. Walton Moore, 1934 (Box 143, Folder 1354)
    - re: Constitutional aspects of intervention in foreign countries for Senator William E. Borah, 1928 (Box 143, Folder 1354)
    - re: Herbert Kraus' answer to Borchard's report on "Diplomatic Protection of Citizens Abroad", undated (Box 143, Folder 1354)
    - re: Law, 1941 (Box 143, Folder 1354)
    - re: Mexican Supreme Court Decision, December 2, 1939, undated (Box 143, Folder 1355)
    - re: Neutrality for Legal Adviser, 1934 (Box 143, Folder 1355)
    - re: Possible study of British controls over neutral trade, 1914-1918 for L. W. Fowles, 1938 (Box 143, Folder 1355)
    - re: Post World War II reconstruction for Council on Foreign Relations, 1943 (Box 143, Folder 1355)
    - re: Prohibitions in international law on state's right to control private property of foreigners, 1930 (Box 143, Folder 1355)
    - re: Proposed Neutrality Act, S. 3474, 1936 (Box 143, Folder 1355)
    - re: Recognition of Russia for Huber, 1933 (Box 143, Folder 1355)
    - re: Report on "Sources of International Law" for Verdross, 1931 (Box 143, Folder 1355)
    - re: Versailles and Brest-Litovsk Treaties, 1934 (Box 143, Folder 1355)
    - re: World Court and advisory opinions for Clark, 1925 (Box 143, Folder 1355)
  - Legal Opinions
    - re: Robert Bosch, G.M.B.H., Stuttgart and Decartelization, 1948? (Box 144, Folder 1356)
    - re: French Domanial Schools in the Saar Basin, undated (Box 144, Folder 1356)
    - re: Tacna-Arica Question, 1919 (Box 144, Folder 1356)
    - re: Use of Continental Shelf, 1945 (Box 144, Folder 1356)
    - re: Dr. Bernhard Weiss and use of war prisoners, post-1929 (Box 144, Folder 1356)
  - Books
    - Bibliography of International Law, 1913 (Box 144, Folder 1357)
    - Guide to the Law of Germany, 1912 (Box 144, Folder 1358)
    - International Law (typescript), undated (Box 144, Folder 1359)
    - The Principle of Respect for Vested Rights of Foreigners. in International Law (typescript), undated (Box 144, Folder 1360)
    - Treatment of Enemy Private Property in Mandated Territory (draft of unpublished book?), post-1938 (Box 144, Folder 1361)
    - Neutrality for the United States (book reviews), 1937-1939 (Box 145, Folder 1362)
  - Book Reviews
    - 1916-1939, 1941-1948 (Box 145, Folder 1363-1366)
  - Pamphlets
    - "Commercial and Financial Interests of the United States in the Carribean", 1917 (Box 145, Folder 1367)
    - "Commercial Laws of England, Scotland, Germany and France", 1915 (Box 145, Folder 1367)
    - "Government Liability in Tort," Part I, 1925 (Box 145, Folder 1368)
    - "Opinion on the Controversy Between Chile and Peru", 1920 (Box 145, Folder 1368)
    - "Opinion on the Questions of the St. Lawrence Waterway", 1944 (Box 145, Folder 1368)
    - "Opinion on the Roumanian-Hungarian Dispute", 1921 (Box 145, Folder 1368)
  - Speeches
    - "Common Sense in Foreign Policy" (press release re: Neutrality Bill), undated (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "World Court", undated (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "World Court" (notes), undated (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "Foreign-owned Property in England" (E. M. Borchard quoted), undated (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "The Adjustment of International Pecuniary Claims", 1916 (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "The Diplomatic Protection of Nationals Abroad" (three lectures), 1923 (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "The International Court", 1923 (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "Declaratory Judgments", 1924 (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "International Relations", 1926 (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "Protection of Citizens Abroad" (release), 1928 (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "Some Celebrated Murder Trials and Their Lesson", 1929 (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "Limitation of Armaments and Freedom of the Seas", 1929 (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "Research in International Law and Relations", 1929 (Box 146, Folder 1369)
    - "International Relations and the American Citizen", 1930 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - "World Court", 1931? (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - "The Protocol for Accession of the United States to the Court", 1931 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - re: Relations with the Soviet Union, 1931 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - "The Policy of the United States in Recognizing New Governments during the Past Twenty-five Years", 1931 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - re: Function and opportunity of law librarians, 1931 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - re: Recognition of the Soviet Union, post-1932 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - "America and a Court of Justice for the Nations", 1932 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - re: Teaching international law, 1933 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - "Nationality, Nationalism and Internationalism: Their Inconsistencies", 1934 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - re: Neutrality in the event of a European war, 1934 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - "Neutrality", 1935 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - "Neutrality" (resume), 1935 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - "Neutrality", 1935 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - re: Neutrality and United States intervention in Asia, post-1935 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - "Neutrality", 1936 (Box 146, Folder 1370)
    - re: Enlarging Supreme Court, 1937 (Box 146, Folder 1371)
    - "Neutrality for the United States", 1937 (Box 146, Folder 1371)
    - "The Spanish Civil War and Its Implications", 1937 (Box 146, Folder 1371)
    - "Neutrality", 1937 (Box 146, Folder 1371)
    - "Democracy and Foreign Policy", 1938 (Box 146, Folder 1371)
    - "Declaratory Judgments and Insurance Litigation", 1938 (Box 146, Folder 1371)
    - Correspondence re: E. M. Borchard's speeches on neutrality, 1937-1938 (Box 146, Folder 1372)
    - "Shall We Change the Neutrality Act?", 1939 (Box 146, Folder 1373)
    - "American Foreign Policy", 1939 (Box 146, Folder 1373)
    - "Neutrality: Extension of Remarks of Hon. John A. Danaher", 1940 (Box 146, Folder 1373)
    - "The Question of United States Neutrality", 1940 (Box 146, Folder 1373)
    - "Neutrality", 1940 (Box 146, Folder 1373)
    - re: Sedition charges, 1942 (Box 146, Folder 1373)
- Biographical Material and Memorabilia, 1920-1945; Series VI; 10" (2 boxes)
  Biographical material and memorabilia is grouped according to subject and arranged chronologically within each folder.
  - Biographical data
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 147, Folder 1374-1375)
    - Miscellaneous memorabilia (Box 147, Folder 1376)
  - Whiting Arches mortgage, 1940-1948 (Box 147, Folder 1377)
  - Round Pond property, 1941-1947 (Box 147, Folder 1378)
  - Purchase of Strumpen-Darrie property, New Canaan, Connecticut, 1946 (Box 147, Folder 1379)